欢迎学习面向开发者的《ChatGPT Prompt工程》课程
Welcome to this course on ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers
我很高兴能邀请到Isa Fulford和我一起授课
I'm thrilled to have with me Iza Fulford to teach this along with me
她是OpenAI的技术人员之一，曾建立了流行的
She is a member of the technical staff of OpenAI and had built the popular
ChatGPT检索插件，她的很大一部分工作是教人们
ChatGPT Retrieval plugin and a large part of her work has been teaching people
如何在产品中使用OEM或大语言模型技术
how to use OEM or large language model technology in products
她还为教人们提示的OpenAI手册做出了贡献
She's also contributed to the OpenAI cookbook that teaches people prompting
所以，很高兴有你参与
So thrilled to have you with you
我也很高兴能在这里与大家分享一些提示的最佳做法
And I'm thrilled to be here and share some prompting best practices with you all
在互联网上有很多关于提示的材料，有一些文章
So there's been a lot of material on the internet for prompting with articles
比如每个人都必须知道的30个提示
like 30 prompts everyone has to know
其中很多都集中在ChatGPT的网络用户界面上
A lot of that has been focused on the ChatGPT web user interface
许多人使用它来完成特定的、通常是一次性的任务
which many people are using to do specific and often one-off tasks
但我认为OEM的力量，大语言模型作为一个开发者也是如此
But I think the power of OEMs, large language models as a developer too
那就是使用API调用OEMs来快速建立软件应用
that is using API calls to OEMs to quickly build software applications
我认为这仍然是非常不被重视的
I think that is still very underappreciated
事实上，我在AI Fund的团队，也就是Deep Learning.AI的姐妹公司
In fact, my team at AI Fund, which is a sister company to Deep Learning.AI
一直在与许多初创公司合作，将这些技术应用于许多不同的应用
has been working with many startups on applying these technologies
在许多不同的应用中
to many different applications
看到OEM APIs能够让开发者快速建立什么，这很令人兴奋
And it's been exciting to see what OEM APIs can enable developers
迅速建立
to very quickly build
所以在这个课程中，我们将与你分享一些可能性
So in this course, we'll share with you some of the possibilities
你可以做什么，以及如何做的最佳实践
for what you can do as well as best practices for how you can do them
有很多材料要涵盖
There's a lot of material to cover
首先，你将学习一些软件开发的提示性最佳实践
First, you'll learn some prompting best practices for software development
然后，我们将涵盖一些常见的用例，总结，推断
Then we'll cover some common use cases, summarizing, inferring
转化、扩展，然后你将使用LLM建立一个聊天机器人
transforming, expanding, and then you'll build a chatbot using an LLM
我们希望这将激发你对新应用的想象力
We hope that this will spark your imagination about new applications
你可以建立的新应用
that you can build
因此，在大型语言模型或LLM的发展中
So in the development of large language models or LLMs
大体上有两种类型的LLM，我把它们称为
there have been broadly two types of LLMs, which I'm going to refer to
作为基础LLM和指令学习LLM
as base LLMs and instruction-tuned LLMs
所以基础LLM已经被训练成基于文本训练数据来预测下一个单词
So base LLM has been trained to predict the next word based on text training data
通常在来自互联网和其他来源的大量数据上进行训练
often trained on a large amount of data from the internet and other sources
来计算出下一个最可能出现的词是什么
to figure out what's the next most likely word to follow
因此，举例来说，如果你要输入这个提示，从前有一只独角兽
So for example, if you were to prompt this, once upon a time there was a unicorn
它可能完成这个，也就是说，它可能预测接下来的几个词是
it may complete this, that is, it may predict the next several words are
和所有独角兽朋友一起生活在一个神奇的森林里
that live in a magical forest with all unicorn friends
但是如果你用法国的首都是什么作为提示
But if you were to prompt this with what is the capital of France
那么根据互联网上的文章可能有
then based on what articles on the internet might have
很有可能的是，基础LLM会以下列方式完成这个任务
it's quite possible that the base LLM will complete this with
什么是法国最大的城市，什么是法国的人口，等等
what is France's largest city, what is France's population, and so on
因为互联网上的文章很有可能是关于法国的问答题列表
because articles on the internet could quite plausibly be lists of quiz questions
关于法国的问答题列表
about the country of France
与此相反，指令学习LLM，发展势头较猛
In contrast, an instruction-tuned LLM, which is where a lot of momentum
LLM的研究和实践一直在进行
of LLM research and practice has been going
一个经过指令学习的LLM已经被训练得能够遵循指令
an instruction-tuned LLM has been trained to follow instructions
因此，如果你要问它，法国的首都是什么？
So if you were to ask it, what is the capital of France
它更有可能输出法国的首都是巴黎
it's much more likely to output something like the capital of France is Paris
因此，指令学习的LLM的典型训练方式是
So the way that instruction-tuned LLMs are typically trained is
你从一个在大量文本数据上训练过的基本LLM开始
you start off with a base LLM that's been trained on a huge amount of text data
然后进一步训练它，用输入和输出来进一步微调它
and further train it, further fine-tune it with inputs and outputs
这些输入和输出都是指令，也是遵循这些指令的良好尝试
that are instructions and good attempts to follow those instructions
然后经常使用一种叫做RLHF的技术进一步完善
and then often further refine using a technique called RLHF
从人类反馈中进行强化学习，以使系统能够更好地
reinforcement learning from human feedback, to make the system better able
提供帮助并遵循指令
to be helpful and follow instructions
因为经过指令学习的LLM已经被训练得很有帮助
Because instruction-tuned LLMs have been trained to be helpful
诚实和无害，因此，举例来说，它们不太可能输出
honest, and harmless, so for example, they're less likely to output
有问题的文本，如有害的输出，与基础LLM相比
problematic text, such as toxic outputs, compared to base LLM
很多实际的使用场景已经转向了
a lot of the practical usage scenarios have been shifting
倾向于指令学习的LLMs
toward instruction-tuned LLMs
你在互联网上找到的一些最佳实践可能更适合于基础LLM
Some of the best practices you find on the internet may be more suited
的最佳实践，但对于今天的大多数实际应用来说，这些最佳实践可能更适合基础LLM
for a base LLM, but for most practical applications today
我们建议大多数人多关注指令学习的LLMs
we would recommend most people instead focus on instruction-tuned LLMs
它们更容易使用，而且由于OpenAI
which are easier to use, and also because of the work of OpenAI
和其他LLM公司的工作，变得更加安全和一致
and other LLM companies, becoming safer and more aligned
因此，本课程将重点介绍指令学习LLM的最佳实践
So this course will focus on best practices for instruction-tuned LLMs
这也是我们建议你在大多数应用中使用的
which is what we recommend you use for most of your applications
在继续之前，我只想感谢来自OpenAI
Before moving on, I just want to acknowledge the team from OpenAI
和DeepLearning.ai的团队
and DeepLearning.ai that had contributed to the materials
的团队，他们为我和Isa将要介绍的材料做出了贡献
that Isa and I will be presenting
我非常感谢Andrew Main, Joe Palermo, Boris Power
I'm very grateful to Andrew Main, Joe Palermo, Boris Power
Ted Sanders，以及来自OpenAI的Lilian Wang
Ted Sanders, and Lilian Wang from OpenAI that were very involved
与我们一起集思广益，审核材料
with us brainstorming materials, vetting the materials to put together
并做成这个简短的课程
the curriculum for this short course
我也很感谢DeepLearning方面的工作
And I'm also grateful on the DeepLearning side for the work
Jeff Ludwig、Eddie Hsu和Tommy Nelson的工作
of Jeff Ludwig, Eddie Hsu, and Tommy Nelson
因此，当你使用一个指令学习LLM时，可以将其看作是
So when you use an instruction-tuned LLM, think of giving instructions
向另一个人发出指令，比如一个聪明但不知道
to another person, say someone that's smart but doesn't know
任务细节的人
the specifics of your task
因此，当一个LLM不工作时，有时是因为指令
So when an LLM doesn't work, sometimes it's because the instructions
不够清楚
weren't clear enough
例如，如果你说，请给我写一些
For example, if you were to say, please write me something
关于艾伦-图灵的东西
about Alan Turing
那么，除此之外，明确以下几点也会有所帮助
Well, in addition to that, it can be helpful to be clear about
你想让文章侧重于他的科学工作
whether you want the text to focus on his scientific work
他的个人生活、他在历史上的作用或其他方向
or his personal life or his role in history or something else
如果你指定了想要文本的语调
And if you specify what you want the tone of the text to be
它是否会根据指定的语调来写，比如像专业记者写的那样
should it take on the tone like a professional journalist would write
还是更像随手写给朋友的轻松语气？
or is it more of a casual note that you dash off to a friend?
这一点是成立的
That holds
LLM会产生你想要的东西
The LLM generates what you want
当然，如果你想象自己在问，比如
And of course, if you picture yourself asking, say
一个刚毕业的大学生为你完成这项任务
a fresh college graduate to carry out this task for you
如果你甚至可以指定他们应该阅读哪些文本片段
if you can even specify what snippets of text they should read
提前写出这篇关于艾伦-图灵的文章
in advance to write this text about Alan Turing
那么，这甚至更好地设置了那个刚毕业的大学生的成功
then that even better sets up that fresh college grad for success
来为你完成这项任务
to carry out this task for you
因此，在接下来的视频中，你会看到关于如何明确和具体的例子
So in the next video, you see examples of how to be clear
这是一个重要的LLM提示原则
and specific, which is an important principle of prompting LLMs
而且你还从Isa那里学到了提示的第二个原则
And you also learn from Isa a second principle of prompting
那就是给LLM时间来思考
that is giving a LLM time to think
因此，让我们继续观看下一个视频
So with that, let's go on to the next video